Liu Wang

+86-19800329692 - Beijing, China - w_liu@bupt.edu.cn - https://liuer-wang.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests lie at the intersection of privacy, security, and software engineering. My work mainly focuses on mobile app analysis, particularly, developing approaches to address the increasing security and privacy concerns within mobile app ecosystems, as well as mining and modeling app data to promote best operational practices across app markets.

EDUCATION

Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications (BUPT)

Beijing, China

Ph.D. in School of Computer Science (National Pilot Software Engineering School) B.E. in School of Computer Science (National Pilot Software Engineering School)

2022 - present 2019 - 2022

Shandong University (SDU)

Jinan, Shandong, China

B.E. in Digital Media Technology, School of Software Engineering

2015 - 2019

PUBLICATIONS (*co-first authorship)

1 Global Prosperity or Local Monopoly? Understanding the Geography of App Popularity Liu Wang, Conghui Zheng, Haoyu Wang, Xiapu Luo, Gareth Tyson, Yi Wang, Shangguang Wang 21st International Conference on Mining Software Repositories (MSR), 2024.

2 MalCertain: Enhancing Deep Neural Network Based Android Malware Detection by Tackling Prediction Uncertainty

Haodong Li, Guosheng Xu, <u>Liu Wang</u>, Xusheng Xiao, Xiapu Luo, Guoai Xu, Haoyu Wang Proceedings of 44th International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE), 2024.

3 Re-measuring the Label Dynamics of Online Anti-Malware Engines from Millions of Samples Jingjing Wang*, <u>Liu Wang*</u>, Feng Dong, Haoyu Wang ACM Internet Measurement Conference (IMC), 2023.

4 WeMinT: Tainting Sensitive Data Leaks in WeChat Mini-Programs

Shi Meng*, <u>Liu Wang*</u>, Shenao Wang, Kailong Wang, Xusheng Xiao, Guangdong Bai, Haoyu Wang The 38th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE), 2023.

5 Ransomware as a Service: Demystifying Android Ransomware Generators

Can Tu, <u>Liu Wang</u>, Yang Xu, Yiping Zhao, Haitao Xu, Haoyu Wang 19th EAI International Conference on Security and Privacy in Communication Networks (SecureComm), 2023.

6 DISTDET: A Cost-Effective Distributed Cyber Threat Detection System

Feng Dong, Liu Wang, Nie Xu, Fei Shao, Haoyu Wang, Ding Li, Xiapu Luo, Xusheng Xiao The 32th USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX Security), 2023.

7 A Deep Dive into the Featured iOS Apps

Liu Wang, Haoyu Wang, Huiyi Wang, Li Li, Yi Wang

The 14th Asia-Pacific Symposium on Internetware (Internetware), 2023.

8 MalWhiteout: Reducing Label Errors in Android Malware Detection

Liu Wang, Haoyu Wang, Xiapu Luo, Yulei Sui

The 37th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE), 2022.

9 Privacy Analysis of Period Tracking Mobile Apps in the Post-Roe v. Wade Era

Zikan Dong, Liu Wang, Hao Xie, Guoai Xu, Haoyu Wang

A-Mobile Workshop, co-located with ASE'22 (A-Mobile), 2022.

10 What Did You Pack in My App? A Systematic Analysis of Commercial Android Packers

Zikan Dong*, Hongxuan Liu*, <u>Liu Wang</u>, Xiapu Luo, Yao Guo, Guoai Xu, Xusheng Xiao, Haoyu Wang ESEC/FSE, Industry Track, 2022.

11 Demystifying "Removed Reviews" in iOS App Store

<u>Liu Wang</u>, Haoyu Wang, Xiapu Luo, Tao Zhang, Shangguang Wang, Xuanzhe Liu <u>ESEC/FSE</u>, Industry Track, 2022.

12 MalRadar: Demystifying Android Malware in the New Era

<u>Liu Wang</u>, Haoyu Wang, Ren He, Ran Tao, Guozhu Meng, Xiapu Luo, Xuanzhe Liu ACM SIGMETRICS/Performance (SIGMETRICS), 2022.

13 A Tale of Two Countries: A Longitudinal Cross-Country Study of Mobile Users' Reactions to the COVID-19 Pandemic Through the Lens of App Popularity

Liu Wang, Haoyu Wang, Yi Wang, Gareth Tyson, Fei Lyu

The 9th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Mobile Software Engineering and Systems (MobileSoft), 2022.

14 A Longitudinal Study of Removed Apps in iOS App Store

Fuqi Lin*, Haoyu Wang*, Liu Wang, Xuanzhe Liu.

Proceedings of the 30th The Web Conference (WWW), 2021.

15 Beyond the Virus: A First Look at Coronavirus-themed Android Malware

Liu Wang, Ren He, Haoyu Wang, Pengcheng Xia, Yuanchun Li, Lei Wu, Yajin Zhou, Xiapu Luo, Yulei Sui, Yao Guo, Guoai Xu

Empirical Software Engineering (EMSE)

16 A Large-Scale Empirical Study of COVID-19 Themed GitHub Repositories

Liu Wang, Ruiqing Li, Jiaxin Zhu, Guangdong Bai, Haoyu Wang

IEEE Computer Society Signature Conference on Computers, Software and Applications (COMPSAC), 2021.

17 Understanding the Impact of COVID-19 on Github Developers: A Preliminary Study

Liu Wang, Ruiqing Li, Jiaxin Zhu, Guangdong Bai, Weihang Su, Haoyu Wang

The 33rd International Conference on Software Engineering & Knowledge Engineering (SEKE), 2021.

18 MadDroid: Characterising and Detecting Devious Ad Content for Android Apps

Tianming Liu, Haoyu Wang, Li Li, Xiapu Luo, Feng Dong, Yao Guo, <u>Liu Wang</u>, Tegawende F. Bissyande, Jacques Klein.

Proceedings of The Web Conference (WWW), 2020.

19 Market-level Analysis of Government-backed COVID-19 Contact Tracing Apps

Huiyi Wang*, Liu Wang*, Haoyu Wang.

The International Workshop on Advances in Mobile App Analysis (A-Mobile), 2020.

HONORS AND AWARDS

· National Scholarship, Chinese Ministry of Education

2021, 2022, 2023

2023

• Outstanding Graduate Student, BUPT

• National Scholarship, Chinese Ministry of Education 2021

SERVICES

TPC Member A-Mobile 2023 PC Member ChinaSoft 2023

Reviewer WWW 2024, EAI SecureComm 2023, Journal of Software (Chinese)

Sub-reviewer PoPETs 2024, FSE 2024

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

• Teaching Assistant, Software Architecture, BUPT

Spring 2024

• Teaching Assistant, Principles of Computer Organization, BUPT

Spring 2020, Spring 2021

VISITINGS AND INTERNS

Visiting PhD student at the Security Pride research group in Huazhong University of Science and Technology
 (HUST), working with Prof. Haoyu Wang.
 Mar 2023 - Aug 2023

• Internship at Sangfor Technologies.

Oct 2021 - Feb 2022